Guide to the Midpeninsula Free University publications
Stanford University Libraries.
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives.
Midpeninsula Free University publications
1966-1970
SC1232
Midpeninsula Free University.
0.5 Linear feet
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives. Stanford University Libraries. 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: speccollref@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
This collection was given by Priscilla Jones Warr, AB 1967, to Stanford University, Special Collections in September 2014.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Biographical/Historical note
The Midpeninsula Free University (MFU) was a free university, operating primarily between 1966 and 1971 on the San Francisco Midpeninsula. The MFU offered an open curriculum; anyone who paid the nominal membership fee of $10 could offer a course in any subject. Courses were publicized in illustrated catalogs, issued quarterly and widely distributed. The MFU had no campus; classes were taught in homes and storefronts. Its magazine-style, illustrated newsletter, The Free You, published articles, features, fiction, poetry, and reviews contributed by both members and nonmembers. The MFU sponsored, be-ins, street concerts, a restaurant, a store, and was actively involved in every aspect of the flourishing counterculture on the Midpeninsula, including the anti-war movement at Stanford University. The MFU was eventually disbanded in July of 1971.
Biographical text excerpted from http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Midpeninsula_Free_University
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of catalogs of course offerings available at the Midpeninsula Free University, as well as its newsletter, The Free You, from 1966-1970. Also included are some Stanford University student publications from the same era.
Access Terms
Warr, Priscilla Jones; Alternative education--California--San Francisco Bay Area; Free schools--California--San Francisco Bay Area.; Midpeninsula Free University--Catalogs.
Collection Contents
- Free University of Berkeley, 1968 Spring (Box 1)
- Free University Press, 1966 Sep 19 (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1970 Spring (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1970 Fall (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1969 Spring (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1969 Winter (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1968 Spring (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1969 Summer (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1967 Fall (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1968 Winter (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1968 Summer (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University, 1968 Fall (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University (No. 1), 1967 Fall (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University (No. 2), 1967 Fall (Box 1)
- Midpeninsula Free University (No. 3), 1967 Fall (Box 1)
- Stanford Free Press, 1970 Apr 28 (Box 1)
- The Colonist, 1970 Oct 23 (Box 1)
- The Experiment, 1966 Fall (Box 1)
- The Experiment, 1966 Winter (Box 1)
- The Experiment, 1967 Spring (Box 1)
- The Experiment: Its Genesis and Intentions, 1960 Fall (Box 1)
- The Free You, 1969 Jul (Box 1)
- The Free You, 1969 Apr (Box 1)
- The Free You, 1969 Mar (Box 1)
- The Free You, 1969 Jan (Box 1)
- The Free You, 1968 Feb (Box 1)
- The Free You, 1968 May (Box 1)
- The Free You, 1968 Jun (Box 1)
- The Free You, 1968 Jul (Box 1)
- The Free You, 1968 Feb (Box 1)
- The Free You (Spring, Vol. 2, Num. 7), 1968 Apr (Box 1)
- The Free You (Spring, Vol. 2, Num. 8), 1968 Apr (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 1), 1968 Jan (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 12), 1968 Aug (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 13), 1968 Aug (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 14), 1968 Aug (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 15), 1968 Oct (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 16), 1968 Oct (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 17), 1968 Nov (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 18), 1968 Nov (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 2), 1968 Jan (Box 1)
- The Free You (Vol. 2, Num. 3), 1968 Jan (Box 1)
- The Free You (Winter), 1968 Apr (Box 1)